# **Anthony Petty**

### Senior Engineer at Wylei

spgwhistler@gmail.com

# Summary

Although skill and experience are required in today's enterprise software industry, there are at least two other things that are critically important, and they can't easily be taught. They are: how to be a team player, and how to be creative.

Over the years I've been developing software professionally, these are two of the many assets I've honed. Again, skill and experience are important; both of which I have. But knowing how to express your ideas in a team setting, and being able to understand the ideas of others are what makes someone a valuable asset.

An individual must be able to quickly learn and understand new ideas and technologies in order to be an adaptable, productive team member. The phrase "quickly learn and understand" is key, because in today's fast paced world, not only technologies, but the ideas and ways to use them change on a daily basis.

In the last fifteen years, I've had the opportunity to work as a full stack software engineer - everything from installing and configuring apache, mysql, memcached, through the server side software like php, node js, and perl, to the client side of things using vanilla js, jquery, flash, and other technologies. And even occasionally the desktop or mobile level of things like browser extensions and native apps.

Creativity on the other hand, isn't just knowledge and understanding, but the ability to apply this knowledge in a unique way that benefits the business. Although it is easy to learn a specific skill, what is not easy is knowing when to use it, and possibly more importantly, when not to use it. Although a new technology might be cool, sometimes it is an old one that is a better fit for the need. Knowing when to make this distinction is critical.

Thank you for taking the time to look through my profile. I believe that my experience and skills listed below are examples of the principals I've discussed.

# Experience

# Senior Engineer at Wylei

April 2013 - Present (7 months)

As the only Senior Engineer at Wylei, I am responsible for a variety of areas including architecture, development, testing, and deployment of our core product: Wylei.js, technical support, maintenance, and development of legacy mobile products, as well as building and maintaining several mobile-first company websites. My responsibilities cover everything from architecture and design, server setup (Amazon EC2 and IIS), software stack (C#, PHP, node.js, and others), development (C#, PHP, and Javascript), deployment (git), to testing and maintenance (node.js and mocha).

#### Senior Software Engineer at Synacor

February 2012 - April 2013 (1 year 3 months)

On the Search and Advertising team, I developed and maintained a Search Engine Results Page integrating results from Google, Ask, and several other vendors that generates tens of millions of dollars in revenue annually and gets millions of hits per month. I also developed the software that displays and manages ads across 40+ portals and websites generating tens of millions of dollars in revenue annually.

#### Software Engineer at Synacor

March 2009 - February 2012 (3 years)

On the Search and Advertising team, I developed and maintained a Search Engine Results Page integrating results from Google, Ask, and several other vendors that generates tens of millions of dollars in revenue annually and gets millions of hits per month. I also developed the software that displays and manages ads across 40+ portals and websites generating tens of millions of dollars in revenue annually.

#### Web Developer at Stock20.com

May 2005 - March 2009 (3 years 11 months)

Built and maintained a stock music website that still serves as a hub for thousands of media professionals world wide that allows them to purchase, download, and manage a library of hundreds of songs. As well as manage licence agreement documentation for each of those songs.

#### Technology Director at Orchard View Church

January 2004 - January 2006 (2 years 1 month)

I developed and maintained a church website that hosted and served media files for sermons. I was also the lead sound engineer, as well as many other miscellaneous tasks and duties.

# **Projects**

#### **Search Engine Results Page**

March 2009 to Present

Members: Anthony Petty, Jesse Thomson, Uday Kodukula

As a Search and Advertising Engineer at Synacor, I've architected and built the SERP (Search Engine Results Page) for 40+ clients. Charter net is just one of them. This page receives millions of page views per month, and makes Synacor tens of millions of dollars in revenue. The current version is built using multiple technologies, including jQuery, Mustache, PHP, MySQL, Moose, Catalyst, XML, Json, and others. The front end uses Synacor's custom PHP framework and jQuery. And the backend is built on a "proxy" type Perl Catalyst service that parses each providers results. This page also showcases several other technologes to make it render correctly cross browser, cross operating system, and in the correct order as each providers results come back.

#### Ads

March 2009 to Present

Members: Anthony Petty, Jesse Thomson, Uday Kodukula

As a developer on the Search and Advertising team, I've architected, built, and maintain the framework that manages and serves ads across Synacor's network for 40+ portals. This network includes several thousand ad placements that get millions of views per month and make Synacor tens of millions of dollars. Ads on Synacor's portals are served with several technologies, including PHP, jQuery, MySQL, several custom Synacor frameworks, ExtJS, Moose, Catalyst, JSON, and several others. The ad placements on each page of each portal are generated with php and they render an iframe to the page. The iframe hits a custom built ad server that runs a Catalyst service which hits a backend datastore. In addition to just serving ads, we do several layers of custom targeting using some similar technologies.

#### Stock20.com

May 2005 to March 2009

Members: Anthony Petty

Built and maintained the stock20.com website and all supporting interfaces. This site is built on top of ZenCart (which was popular in 2005), but customized quite heavily to support the type of media serving required. There are several custom Adobe Flex applications running that allow users to find, purchase, and download both the music and the supporting custom licence agreements.

# Skills & Expertise

**PHP** 

**jQuery** 

**MySQL** 

**JavaScript** 

Git

**CSS** 

**Apache** 

**Web Development** 

**LAMP** 

Perl

**REST** 

**HTML** 

Moose

Catalyst

**JSON** 

**JSONP** 

**XML** 

CSS3

**Subversion** 

**Online Advertising** 

**Search Advertising** 

**Organic Search** 

Google API

**JIRA** 

Scrum

Waterfall

Agile Methodologies
Selenium
TDD
PHPUnit
Test Driven Development
Bash
Android Development
iOS development
IIS
Amazon EC2

# Education

## Oakridge High School

1997 - 2001

## **Interests**

new technologies, programming languages, electronics, solving complex problems

# **Anthony Petty**

Senior Engineer at Wylei

spgwhistler@gmail.com



Contact Anthony on LinkedIn